JORDAN JORDANOV

Software Engineer, Assistant Professor, PhD Student

0879317180 • jordanov.jordan@ue-varna.bg • https://profjordanov.github.io • Varna, Bulgaria

Summary

Very ambitious, creative and quick-learning full stack software engineer with leadership, programming and architectural skills. I have experience, and knowledge in application development with .NET platform (C#, ASP.NET, Web API, Signal R, Entity Framework, SQL server), JavaScript (Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Angular.js React.js), Microsoft Azure Cloud Computing Services. Also understanding of algorithmic problems and data structures.

Education

University of Economics - Varna Varna, BG
PhD in Computer Science 2021 - Ongoing

Software University Sofia, BG
C# and JS path | GPA: 5.00 / 6.00 2015 - 2019

University of Economics - Varna Varna, BG
Masters in Computer Science | GPA: 5.5 / 6.00 2014 - 2019

Experience

Heidelberg Materials

2019 - Ongoing

Varna, BG

Global IT Center is an in-house IT hub of Heidelberg Materials, one of the world's largest integrated manufacture.

- Worked in a team large software team, delivering features on a daily basis.
- Developed a mobile application & admin panel for logistic process.
- Owned more than 50 production deployments with more than 90% success rate.
- Increased the number of customers by 35%

Senior Full Stack Developer

- Improved load times by 20% by refactoring to separate IO operations from business logic and reduce unneeded API calls.
- Worked very closely with the stakeholders by holding daily meetings and doing a demo at least once a week.

University of Economics - Varna

Varna, BG

2020 - Ongoing

Assistant Professor University of Economics - Varna is the oldest economic university in Bulgaria.

- Prepared and provided classes in computer science for 5 faculties of the university
- Represent university during scientific events and Olympiads

CluneTech Varna, BG

Full Stack Developer 2017 - 2019

CluneTech is a suite of companies that provides industry-leading solutions to simplify global business.

- Worked with team of 30 members
- Launched a new product line that constitutes 24% of business portfolio
- Migrated most of the backend services from .NET 4.5 to .NET Core
- Integrated with external payment systems using TDD

Skills

 ${\sf Client\text{-}Side:}\ {\sf HTML\cdot CSS\cdot JS}\ \cdot {\sf React\cdot Redux\cdot TypeScript\cdot Bootstrap\cdot React}\ {\sf Native}$

Server-side:

 $ASP. \ NET \cdot EF \cdot MSSQL \cdot PostgreSQL \cdot TensorFlow \cdot NodeJS \cdot Redis \cdot Azure \cdot MongoDB \cdot HTTP/2 \cdot gRPC \cdot RabbitMQ$

Skills

Development & Operations:

Docker · Kubernetes · Github · GitLab · Lean · Argocd · Scrum · Agile · GIT · Azure DevOps · ELK · Jira

Projects

Custom eLearn mini-system

https://students-manager.site/

Students learning process management system in ASP. NET Core and Azure.

- Quiz for students
- Homework, grading and discussion management
- Chatbot for mock examination
- Application uses a combination between domain-driven design and functional programming in C#. It features DDD, CQRS, event-sourcing, 100% integration test coverage, CI and CD, REST with HATEOAS, Docker setup and much more

Publications

TemJournal - https://temjournal.com/

2022

Digitalization of Educational Services with Regard to Policy for Information Security Pavel Petrov, Ivan Kuyumdzhiev, Rami Malkawi, Georgi Dimitrov, Jordan Jordanov

Languages

Bulgarian Native English Proficient Russian Beginner

Strengths

Contribution to academic success.

Communication

Working from a young age in the summer resorts.

Presentation skills

 $\downarrow_{\rm Z}^{\rm A}$ Research

Working on doctoral thesis.

Achievements

Softuniada 2020

Event for competitive programming.

Innovation Camp by DSKBank Experience the steps of a profound innovation.

Employee of the year

Awarded employee of the year in my
first company.